A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Counsel's Office, Series 10 FA358
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Michael Whiteman, 1963-1974; 4; 80 Document Box(es)
  - Legislation - Gubernatorial Election Campaign, October-November 1970 (Box 71, Folder 753)
    Press releases: noise pollution, elementary and secondary education, "Flexible Federalism," senior citizens, State Student Corps., State University expansion, increase jobs, universal health insurance, transportation, "More Housing Now," social services: put welfare recipients to work, increase electrical power, "End Drug Abuse," mental retardation, rights of individuals, mental health care, maintaining a healthy agricultural economy, "For Working People" (welfare to work), parks and recreation, law enforcement, survival for culture and the arts.
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 754)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 755)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 756)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 757)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 758)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 759)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 760)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 761)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 762)
  - Not Used (Box 71, Folder 763)
  - Legislation - Nelson A. Rockefeller Press Releases, April 27-November 1, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 764)
    Various campaign subjects.
  - Legislation - Program Suggestions, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 765)
  - Legislation - Program Suggestions, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 766)
    Education, recreation and culture, transportation, general government, natural resources, social development, crime control, housing, economic development.
  - Legislation - Drafts of 1970 Annual Message, 1969 (Box 72, Folder 767)
  - Legislation - First Draft of 1970 Annual Message, 1969 (Box 72, Folder 768)
    Survey, public attitudes about state spending, particularly education.
  - Legislative Files - Budget for 1972, August-December 1971 (Box 72, Folder 769)
    Proposals and memos.
  - Legislative Files - Budget, 1972-1973 (Box 72, Folder 770)
    Budget bills of special significance.
  - Legislative Files - Budget, 1972 (Box 72, Folder 771)
    Budget bills, lawsuit -- "Comptroller vs. Governor"
  - Legislative Files - Status Sheets, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 772)
  - Legislative Files - Program, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 773)
    Assignments, reintroduction of 1971 bills.
  - Legislative Files - Annual Message, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 774)
    Memos, drafts of message.
  - Legislative Files - Domestic International Sales Corporation (DISC), ca. 1972 (Box 73, Folder 775)
  - Legislative Files - Supplemental Budget, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 776)
    Summary of 1972 budget bills, memos on benefits to survivors of those killed at the Attica Riot of 1971.
  - Legislative Files - Highway Financing Bill, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 777)
  - Legislative Files - Legislation, 1971-1972 (Box 73, Folder 778)
    Correspondence, criticism of Narcotics Addiction Control Commission by New York District Attorney Frank Hogan.
  - Legislative Files - Annual Message Breakdown, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 779)
  - Legislative Files - Departmentals, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 780)
  - Legislative Files - Social Services Law Revision, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 781)
  - Legislative Files - Abandoned Autos, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 782)
  - Legislative Files - Adirondacks - Scenic Easement, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 783)
  - Legislative Files - Constitutional Law Amendment on Barge Canal Tolls, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 784)
  - Legislative Files - Consumer Protection in 1972 Program, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 785)
  - Legislative Files - Correctional Facilities Construction, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 786)
  - Legislative Files - Correctional Reform, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 787)
    Jones Committee: memos, draft of special message to legislature, press release.
  - Legislative Files - Court Reform, 1972 (Box 73, Folder 788)
    Judicial removal memos.
  - Legislative Files - Court Reform in 1972 Program (Box 74, Folder 789)
    Memos, correspondence, program bills, concurrent resolution.
  - Legislative Files - Courts, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 790)
    Ready Rule.
  - Legislative Files - Crime, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 791)
  - Legislative Files - Dormitory Authority Membership, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 792)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller handwritten note re: removing Chancellor of State University as "ex officio" member and having Dormitory Authority members appointed by Governor rather than Board of Regents.
  - Legislative Files - Education - Federal Aid Resolution, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 793)
    Memos re: "Nixon Plan for Value Added Taxes (VAT) and Federal Aid to Education," Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, drafts of concurrent resolution.
  - Legislative Files - Financing Higher Education, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 794)
    Memos and draft bill.
  - Legislative Files - Election Law Reform, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 795)
  - Legislative Files - Environmental Conservation Recodification, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 796)
    Correspondence on Senator Anderson proposal to merge and consolidate Department of Commerce, Office of Planning Services and Office for Local Government into new Department of Commerce and Local Government.
  - Legislative Files - Government Reorganization, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 797)
  - Legislative Files - Health, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 798)
    Nursing bill, drug substitution or equivalency of generics, health insurance consumer protection.
  - Legislative Files - Housing, New York City, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 799)
  - Legislative Files - Housing, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 800)
    Report (1970), memos.
  - Legislative Files - Human Rights Appeal Board, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 801)
  - Legislative Files - Labor - 1972 Program (Box 74, Folder 802)
    Memos, reports, Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA).
  - Legislative Files - Mental Hygiene - 1972 Program (Box 74, Folder 803)
    Recodification, unified services.
  - Legislative Files - Office of Employee Relations, 1972 (Box 74, Folder 804)
    Memo re: extension of retirement benefits.
  - Legislative Files - No-Fault Insurance - 1972 Program (Box 74, Folder 805)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller press releases, correspondence, editorials, draft legislation.
  - Legislative Files - Parks Reorganization and Codification - 1972 Program (Box 75, Folder 806)
    Memos, draft legislation.
  - Legislative Files - Parks Reorganization and Codification, 1972 (Box 75, Folder 807)
  - Counsel's Office - Departmental Lists, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 808)
    Bills to be submitted to legislature.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Sheets, 1973 (Box 75, Folder 809)
  - Counsel's Office - Annual Message, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 810)
    Memos, message breakdown.
  - Counsel's Office - Special Message, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 811)
    Drugs, press release January 10, 1973, letter from William Tendy, Organized Crime Task Force (OCTF) -- death penalty.
  - Counsel's Office - Status Sheets, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 812)
    Legislative check lists, annual message breakdown, "Ought to" list, "Must" list.
  - Counsel's Office - Legislature, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 813)
    Members and committee assignments, Senate rules.
  - Counsel's Office - Budget, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 814)
    Memos from departments, letter to Attorney General Lefkowitz from Robert Fischer re: Attica Prison riot prosecution progress and outlook, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, budget deficiency legislation.
  - Counsel's Office - Budget Bills, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 815)
    Memos re: budget bills and budget proposals.
  - Counsel's Office - Legislation, 1973; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 76, Folder 816)
    Memos, beer pricing, crime victims compensation, scenic easements.
  - Counsel's Office - Legislation, 1973; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 76, Folder 817)
    Battery Park City bills, housing, redevelopment, Nelson A. Rockefeller press releases.
  - Counsel's Office - Legislation, 1973; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 76, Folder 818)
    Insurance -- open rating, report, proposed bill.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program (Box 76, Folder 819)
    Energy conservation, public intoxication, parking in New York City, Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), Agricultural policy.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Consumer Protection - General (Box 76, Folder 820)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, prescription drug bills, installment buying bills, default judgements.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Consumer Protection (Box 77, Folder 821)
    1. Fair trade laws, Corning Glass 2. register auto repair shops 3. register television repair shops
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Criminal Justice, Folder 1 of 6 (Box 77, Folder 822)
    State Commission on Correction -- abolish and re-create in Executive Department.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Criminal Justice, Folder 2 of 6 (Box 77, Folder 823)
    Court reform, New York State Bar Association proposal, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release -- state financing of court operations.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Criminal Justice, Folder 3 of 6 (Box 77, Folder 824)
    Bypass of grand jury by prosecutor.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Criminal Justice, Folder 4 of 6 (Box 77, Folder 825)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller press releases -- pier security, jury selection, hand guns.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Criminal Justice, Folder 5 of 6 (Box 77, Folder 826)
    Memo New York City Police retirement -- pension of person under investigation.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Criminal Justice, Folder 6 of 6 (Box 77, Folder 827)
    Statewide prosecutor -- expand powers, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, memo.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Higher Education Financing (Box 77, Folder 828)
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Community Colleges (Box 77, Folder 829)
    Memos, reports, correspondence.
  - Counsel's Office - 1973 Program - Primary and Secondary Education (Box 77, Folder 830)
    Proposal to create education inspector general - reports, memos.
  - Counsel's Office - Education Department Reorganization, 1973 (Box 77, Folder 831)
  - Counsel's Office - Primary and Secondary Education, 1973 (Box 77, Folder 832)
    State aid and local financing -- proposals and studies.
  - Counsel's Office - Environment, 1973 (Box 77, Folder 833)
    Phosphates from detergents -- memos, reports, industry objectives, Nelson A. Rockefeller meeting with manufacturers; scenic easements memos.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 78, Folder 834)
    Environment -- Adirondack Park: draft legislation, preliminary plan for public hearings, Sierra Club report.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 78, Folder 835)
    Environment -- Adirondack Park: draft legislation, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release (March 21, 1973), program bill.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 78, Folder 836)
    Environment -- Adirondack Park: maps, Adirondack Park Agency recommendations, Assembly vote, notes, draft vote of Assembly delay bill.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 837)
    Environment -- Barge Canal: proposal to transfer jurisdiction of canal from Department of Transportation to Department of Recreation and Parks.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 838)
    Environment: 1. pollution abatement -- JDA financing 2. solid waste regulation, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, outline, draft bill 3. tidal wetlands -- memos
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 839)
    Health -- Medical Care Facilities Finance Agency: memos, proposed legislation, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 840)
    Health -- housing and community development: memos, proposed legislation to increase bonding of Urban Development Corporation.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 841)
    Mass transportation -- Port of New York Authority: legislation memos 1. extension of Port Authority Trans-Hudson (PATH) tubes and 2. develop Kennedy and Newark airport rail access facilities
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 842)
    State takeover of Medicaid and public assistance: correspondence, program bills.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973 (Box 78, Folder 843)
    Medicaid and public assistance: restoration of 10% cutbacks.
  - Counsel's Office - Program Files, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 844)
    Mental health -- unified services: memos, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, notes, program bill and memo.
  - Counsel's Office - Narcotics, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 845)
    1. Hardt Commission report draft on penalties for sale and possession 2. January 1973 issue of district attorney newsletter 3. remarks of John F. O'Mara, President of New York State District Attorneys' Association before Senate and Assembly Code Committee, February 6, 1973 4. letter to Michael Whiteman from William Tendy, New York State Organized Crime Task Force (OCTF) re: penalties 5. chart: New York State District Attorneys' Association drug crimes and penalties proposed 6. New York State District Attorneys' Association legislative proposals
  - Counsel's Office - Narcotics - Rockefeller Drug Laws, 1973; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 79, Folder 846)
    Correspondence, reports, draft legislation, comparison charts, codes committee hearing schedule, testimony before codes committee.
  - Counsel's Office - Narcotics - Rockefeller Drug Laws, 1973; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 79, Folder 847)
    Reports, correspondence, staff meeting with Nelson A. Rockefeller, draft legislation.
  - Counsel's Office - Narcotics - Rockefeller Drug Laws, 1973; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 79, Folder 848)
    Briefing book.
  - Counsel's Office - Narcotics (Box 79, Folder 849)
    Bounties for pushers, forfeiture of escheat, life sentence for pushers, life for violent crimes under the influence, youthful offenders, 100 judges.
  - Counsel's Office - Addiction (Box 79, Folder 850)
    Narcotic Addiction Control Commission program civil commitment, increase NACC program capacity.
  - Counsel's Office - No Fault Insurance, 1973 (Box 80, Folder 851)
    Correspondence, memos, legislation.
  - Counsel's Office - Pari-Mutuel Betting - Off-Track Betting, 1973 (Box 80, Folder 852)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, memos, reports, vote.
  - Counsel's Office - State Government, 1973 (Box 80, Folder 853)
    State coordinating committee, regional development councils and advisory councils.
  - Counsel's Office - Worker's Benefits, 1973 (Box 80, Folder 854)
    Program bills -- increase worker's compensation benefits, eliminate strikers' benefits, dependents' benefits under unemployment benefits, silicosis benefits, reports, memos, legislation.
  - Counsel's Office - Job and Workers, 1973 (Box 80, Folder 855)
    Proposed constitutional amendment -- increase financing by Job Development Authority, Long Island Railroad Strike, farm labor, Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) state implementation, supervision of private pension and welfare funds, public employee pensions, jobless social benefits.